Sahil Khose

(+91) 70573 70005 \Leftrightarrow sahilkhose18@gmail.com Website \Leftrightarrow LinkedIn \Leftrightarrow GitHub \Leftrightarrow Google Scholar

PROFILE

My research experience and interests are in the field of Computer Vision, Continual Learning, Zero-Shot Learning, Semi-supervised Learning, NLP and Self-supervised Learning. Solving deep learning problems using a limited (ideally zero) amount of data is what piques my interest.

EDUCATION

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal

2018-Present

B. Tech in Computer and Communication Engineering (Minor in Big Data)

CGPA: 8.49/10

EXPERIENCE

Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore

Jul 2021 – Present

AI Research Assistant

Advisors - Dr. Suresh Sundaram & Dr. Chandan Gautam

- Working on Continual Generalized Zero-Shot Learning(CGZSL).
- Working on Sketch Based Image Retrieval and Instance Segmentation in a CGZSL setting.

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal

Apr 2021 – Present

AI Research Assistant

Advisor - Dr. Harish Kumar JR

- \bullet Developed a model for ${\bf fovea}$ ${\bf disc}$ ${\bf segmentation}$ using semi-supervised segmentation.
- Working on macular degeneration classification using multi-task deep learning.

Project MANAS(AI/Robotics team at Manipal)

Feb 2019 - May 2021

AI Perception Developer

- Worked for the 27th Intelligent Ground Vehicle Competition held in Michigan, USA.
- Worked on building a level 2-3 autonomy car on Indian roads for the Mahindra \$1Million Challenge.

Publications

BERT based Transformers lead the way in Extraction of Health Information from Social Media Published in proceedings of NAACL 2021 GitHub | aclweb Apr 2021

- Top performer on Task 1 & Task 6 and special recognition on multi-task performance in shared tasks of SMM4H.
- ADE classification: Handled a 1:13 class imbalance dataset. Trained RoBERTa and BioBERT. Achieved valid F1: 85% test F1: 61%. [Rank: 1] (ADE: Adverse Drug Effects)
- ADE span detection: RoBERTa based NER pipeline. Achieved valid F1: 54% test F1: 50%. [Rank: 2]
- COVID classification: RoBERTa, DeBERTa, Covid-Twitter BERT, BERTweet, and ensemble were trained for the 3 classification problem. Achieved valid F1: 99% test F1: 94%. [Rank: 2]

Semi-Supervised Classification and Segmentation on High Resolution Aerial Images

Accepted at Tackling Climate Change with ML workshop at NeurIPS 2021 GitHub | arXiv | Blog | Demo May 2021

- Handled a dataset of 1450 images with just 25% labelled data and a class imbalance of 1:6.
- ResNet18 with our implemented semi-supervised pipeline fetched 96.70% test accuracy beating the best model of the FloodNet paper by a huge 3% margin with less than half the parameters.
- Implemented a semi-supervised multi-class segmentation pipeline for 10 class segmentation. DeepLabv3+ with EfficientNet-B3 backbone fetched us 52.23% mIoU on the test set.
- Analytically and visually analyzed our performance for segmentation on multiple architectures like **UNet**, **PSPNet**, **DeepLabV3+** with and without **pseudo label** based semi-supervised learning.

Extraction of Color Information from Images for Generation of Colored Outlines and Sketches Accepted at New in ML workshop at NeurIPS 2021 GitHub | arXiv | Demo Aug 2021

- Applied image processing techniques and **unsupervised learning** to quantize and extract colors in images and render sketches with colored outlines.
- Used conditional GANs for image to colored-sketch generation with the help of colorspace manipulation.

A Studious Approach to Semi-Supervised Learning

Accepted at ICBINB workshop at NeurIPS 2021 GitHub | arXiv

Sep 2021

- Performed distillation for semi-supervised learning producing better and smaller models for real-time deployment proving fewer the labels, the more this approach benefits from a smaller student network
- We experimented on: EfficientNet-b5, ResNet18, and MobileNet-V3-Large to demonstrate the benefit of model compression on four label splits, highlighting the semi-supervised advantage and model optimization.

Age-Related Macular Degeneration using Semi-Supervised Learning

Submitting to **IEEE TMI journal** (Advisor: Dr. Harish Kumar JR)

Oct 2021

- Developed a semi-supervised segmentation pipeline to train on **484** images for fovea disc segmentation for opthamology diagnosis. Class imbalance as high as **1:99** in every image
- Performed semi-supervised classification on a dataset of **627** datapoints. The task being age-related macular degeneration with an imbalance of **1:5:5**. Our proposed method surpasses most of the **SOTA results**.

Projects

Self-Driving Car and AGV – Project MANAS GitLab

Feb 2019 – May 2021

• Successfully implemented Lane Detection, Speed Bump Detection, Driving Imitation System, Depth map generation using multiple cameras and LiDAR input using Deep Learning.

StackGAN for text to image generation GitHub

Oct 2020

• Implemented the **StackGAN** (2 stages GAN) architecture from scratch in PyTorch with enhanced BERT data representations for synthesizing photo-realistic bird images from their textual descriptions.

QANet for SQuAD 2.0 (Question-Answering) GitHub

Sep 2020

• Implemented the **QANet** architecture from scratch in PyTorch consisting exclusively of convolution and self-attention, achieving **13x** faster train & **9x** faster inference than the BIDAF model (previous SOTA).

Stock Prediction using Hyper Graphs GitHub

Aug 2020

• Developed a Hypergraph structured dataset and built a Hypergraph NN based architecture with **Hypergraph** CNN, BERT, LSTM and attention network for stock prediction of 500 stocks over time.

Neural Machine Translation GitHub | Demo

Jul 2020

• Built a Neural Machine Translation model using a seq2seq bi-LSTM architecture with attention and hybrid character-word level language modelling. Achieved **37 BLEU** on Spanish-English translation.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Project MANAS stood World Rank 1 at the 27th Intelligent Ground Vehicle Competition (IGVC 2019).
- IGVC Awards: Interoperability 1st, Design 2nd, Cybersecurity 3rd, Grand prize Lescoe Cup.
- Project MANAS won the Million Dollar Mahindra Rise Prize (top 13 out of 153 teams in India).
- Led a team of 3 to secure an All India Rank 19 in the Flipkart GRiD 2.0 level 1.
- Led a team of 4 to secure Rank 1 in Google Hash Code 2020 in Manipal hub, ranked 500 in India.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C++, Java, C

Tools and Libraries: PyTorch, NumPy, Tensorflow, OpenCV, Matplotlib

Experienced in: Computer Vision, NLP, Zero-Shot Learning, Semi-supervised learning, Distillation

EXTRACURRICULAR

FruitPunch AI (AI expertise head)

Aug 2021 – Present

Established the first international chapter of FruitPunch AI, a non profit organization headquartered in Europe. Currently engaged in building the community and promoting AI for social good initiatives

YouTube Channel (Online Educator)

 $Jun\ 2021-Present$

Conducts weekly presentations on cutting edge research papers in the field of AI.

Research Society Manipal (AI division mentor)

Nov 2020 - Present

Mentoring and guiding several students to pursue research in the field of Deep Learning.

NAACL reviewer

Mar 2021

Reviewed multiple research papers as a part of the review committee for SMM4H Workshop.